Mercury Press Records
Mercury Press Records
1946-1969
Mercury Press
45 linear ft.
Correspondence and editorial files from the American publisher. Vast majority are related to Fantasy & Science Fiction Magazine with a few from Venture and True Crime Detective.
2680668
Biographical History
Mercury Press was created in the late 1930s by Lawrence Spivak as a publisher for The American Mercury, a popular magazine of American culture and criticism. The company and its various branches, including Mystery House and Fantasy House, soon branched out into other magazines, including Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine (1941) and The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction.
The Magazine of Fantasy & Science Fiction, later renamed Fantasy & Science Fiction and sometimes referred to as F&SF, published its first issue in 1949. Mercury Press continued as the publisher for more than fifty years, until the magazine moved to Spilogale, Inc. in 2001. Initially the magazine was published quarterly (1949-1950) but by 1952 it was a monthly magazine, which it remained until 1991. From 1991-2008 F&SF published 11 issues per year, until in 2009 it dropped back to a bimonthly publication.
Notable authors published in F&SF include Harlan Ellison, Thomas Disch, Stephen King, Shirely Jackson, Robert Heinlein, Fritz Leiber, Kurt Vonnegut, and many many more.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Mercury Press Records contain correspondence and production files for The Magazine of Fantasy & Science Fiction and a few other publications. The collection consists of two large parts, processed and arranged separately; material relating to a particular author therefore may be found in several locations in the collection. Researchers should review the entire finding aid to ensure locating all relevant material.
Part I consists of questionnaires, manuscripts, published material, and a subject file.
Questionnaires contains replies to a questionnaire sent to subscribers of Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine as part of a survey conducted by Mercury Press to determine what type of people read science fiction. On the back of many of the questionnaires are additional comments by the subscribers. There are no dates on these.
Manuscripts, which comprise the bulk of this collection, are for the most part original typescripts with corrections and printers notes, but also included are galleys, xerox copies, and printed copies. When the manuscripts are anything but original typescripts, it is indicated on the inventory. The manuscripts include short stories, novels, poems, plays, and reviews; among the authors represented are Poul Anderson, Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, Gore Vidal, Damon Knight, Keith Laumer, Jack London, Robert Silverberg, and Robert Heinlein. These stories appeared in Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine and Venture Magazine, published by Mercury Press.
Published material consists of books and periodicals -- American and English editions of The Best From Fantasy and Science Fiction, issues of Venture Magazine and its Spanish edition Minotaure, published in Argentina, and copies of Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine. All published material has been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging; please refer to to locate these items.
A small group of Subject files completes the collection, consisting of editorials and tables of contents for Venture Magazine and Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine.
Part II consists of correspondence, and editorial and production files relating to two magazines published by Mercury Press.
Correspondence is subdivided into fan mail, incoming, and outgoing. Authors represented here include Forrest Ackerman, Isaac Asimov, Peter S. Beagle, Ray Bradbury, Marion Zimmer Bradley, Robert Heinlein, Cyril Korbluth, Walter M. Miller, Andre Norton, Clifford Simak, Theodore Sturgeon, Manly Wade Wellman, and many more.
The remaining two series consist of files relating to Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine and True Crime Detective. Each of these two series is subdivided into editorial files (the majority of which are manuscripts of stories), financial records, and production records. The Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine series also contains some memorabilia and assorted other items.
Arrangement of the Collection
Part I - Correspondence (questionnaire) is arranged by age of respondent. Manuscripts are arranged alpabetically by type and then by title. Published material has been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Part II - Correspondence is arranged either alphabetically (incoming) or chronologically (outgoing). Fantasy and Science Fiction files and True Crime Detective files are subdivided into editorial files, financial records, and production records, and within that arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
See also the
Fantasy and Science Fiction Magazine Collection
. In addition, has a number of manuscript collections related to science fiction and fantasy authors and publishers; please refer to for a complete listing. In addition, numerous science fiction books, pamphlets, serials and other items are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection; please be sure to search for these related materials.
Other Related Finding Aids
An up-to-date author index to the complete run of F&SF magazine is available online at http://www.hycyber.com/SF/fsf_aa.html.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science fiction; Publishing, printing and book arts; Mercury Press.; Magazine of fantasy and science fiction (Cornwall, Conn.); Fantasy & science fiction.; True crime detective.; Venture magazine.; Fantasy fiction -- Publishing.; Fantasy fiction, American -- Periodicals.; Science fiction -- Publishing.; Science fiction, American -- Periodicals.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Fan mail.; Galley proofs.; Inventories.; Manuscripts for publication.; Page proofs.; Publishers.; Tear sheets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mercury Press, 1969.
Inventory
- Questionnaires (Part I)
  - Returned by under 18 year olds, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Returned by 18-30 year olds, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Returned by 30-45 year olds, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Returned by 45-60 year olds, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 2, 3)
  - Returned by 60 years old, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Returned by unidentified age group, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 3)
- Manuscripts (Part I)
  - Aandahl, Vance
    - Cogi Drove His Car Through Hell, Aug. 1961; article (Box 4)
    - A Crown of Rank Fumiter, Sept. 1964; article (Box 4)
    - Darfgarth, July 1962; article (Box 4)
    - It's A Great Big Wonderful Universe, Aug. 1960; article (Box 4)
    - The Riddle Song, 1963; article (Box 4)
    - The Unfortunate Mr. Morky, Dec. 1962; article (Box 4)
    - The Were Martini, 1963; article (Box 4)
    - When Lilacs Last in The Dooryard Bloomed, May 1962; article (Box 4)
  - Aarons, Edward S.
    - The Communicators, June 1958; article (Box 4)
    - The Makers of Destiny, Sept. 1959; book (Box 4)
  - Adams, Louis J.A.
    - Dark Conception, Sept. 1964; article (Box 4)
  - Agate, Mrs.
    - Sally Aromsen's Crime Wave, May 1960; article (Box 4)
  - Albee, George
    - The Top, Aug. 1962; article (Box 4)
  - Aldiss, Brian W.
    - Burning Question, Oct. 1961; article (Box 4)
    - Have Your Hatreds Ready, May 1958; article (Box 4)
    - A Kind of Artistry, Dec. 1962; article (Box 4)
    - The New Father Christmas, Jan. 1958; article (Box 4)
    - Poor Little Warrior, April 1958; article (Box 4)
    - Evergreen, Dec. 1961; book (Box 4)
    - Hothouse, undated; book (Box 4)
    - Nomansland, April 1961; book (Box 4)
    - Timberline, Sept. 1961; book (Box 4)
    - The Saliva Tree, undated; book (Box 4)
    - Undergrowth, July 1961; book (Box 4)
    - Space Burial, undated; poem (Box 4)
  - Alpert, Hollis
    - The Simian Problem, July 1960; article (Box 5)
  - Amis, Kingsley
    - Something Strange, June 1961; article (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Karen
    - I Can See It Now, June 1958; article (Box 5)
    - Landscape With Sphinxes, Nov. 1962; article (Box 5)
    - Treaty in Tartesso's, May 1963; article (Box 5)
    - In Memoriam: Henry Kuttner, May 1958; poem (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Poul
    - Backwardness, Nov. 1958; article (Box 5)
    - Cold Victory, May 1957; article (Box 5)
    - For the Duration, Sept. 1957; article (Box 5)
    - Full Pack, Oct. 1957; article (Box 5)
    - Journey's End, Feb. 1957; article (Box 5)
    - The Last of the Deliverers, Feb. 1958; article (Box 5)
    - License, April 1957; article (Box 5)
    - Life Cycle, July 1957; article (Box 5)
    - The Martian Crown Jewels, April 1959; article (Box 5)
    - The Martyr, March 1960; article (Box 5)
    - Operation Incubus, Oct. 1959; article (Box 5)
    - Operation Salamander, Jan. 1957; article (Box 5)
    - The Peacemongers, Dec. 1957; article (Box 5)
    - Survival Technique, March 1957; article (Box 5)
    - Welcome, Oct. 1960; article (Box 5)
    - Admiralty, June 1965; book (Box 5)
    - Arsenal Port, April 1964; book (Box 5)
    - Brave Be A King, Aug. 1959; book (Box 5)
    - The Game of Glory, March 1958; book (Box 5)
    - Marque and Reprisal, 1965; book (Box 5)
    - No Truce With Kings, 1963; book (Box 6)
    - The Only Game In Town, Jan. 1960; book (Box 6)
    - Progress, Jan. 1962; book (Box 6)
    - Undiplomatic Immunity, Nay 1957; book (Box 6)
    - Virgin Planet, Jan. 1957; book (Box 6)
    - Wildcat, Nov. 1958; book (Box 6)
    - Ballade of an Artificial Satellite, Nov. 1958; poem (Box 6)
  - Angus, Douglas
    - About Time To Go South, Oct. 1957; article (Box 6)
  - Anvil, Christopher
    - Sabotage, Nov. 1966; article (Box 6)
  - Apostolides, Alex
    - Sandy Had A Tiger, Aug. 1958; article (Box 6)
  - Arthur, Robert
    - The Devil's Garden, Sept. 1959; article (Box 6)
    - Garvey's Ghost, April 1962; article (Box 6)
    - The Hero Equation, June 1959; article (Box 6)
    - Jabez O'Brien and Davy Jones Locker, June 1965; article (Box 6)
    - The Man With the Golden Hand, Nov. 1958; article (Box 6)
    - Miracle on Main Street, June 1960; article (Box 6)
    - Obstinate Uncle Otis, April 1958; article (Box 6)
  - Asimov, Isaac
    - About Time, April 1960; article (Box 7)
    - The Atmosphere of the Moon, March 1958; article (Box 7)
    - Balancing the Books, July 1966; article (Box 7)
    - The Battle of the Eggheads, July 1959; article (Box 7)
    - BB or Not BB, That is the Question, Aug. 1966; article (Box 7)
    - Behind the Teacher's Back, Aug. 1965; article (Box 7)
    - Beyond Pluto, July 1960; article (Box 7)
    - The Big Bang, 1958, May, article (Box 7)
    - The Bug-Eyed Monster, June 1960; article (Box 7)
    - Buy Jupiter, May 1958; article (Box 7)
    - By Jove, May 1962; article (Box 7)
    - The By-Product of Science Fiction, April 1957; article (Box 7)
    - Catching Up With Newton, Dec. 1958; article (Box 7)
    - Catskills in the Sky, Aug. 1960; article (Box 7)
    - The Certainly of Uncertainly, April 1964; article (Box 7)
    - C For Celeritas, Nov. 1959; article (Box 7)
    - The Clash of the Cymbals, July 1958; article (Box 7)
    - Death in the Laboratory, Sept. 1965; article (Box 7)
    - Dethronement, Nov. 1961; article (Box 7)
    - The Diadem, June 1962; article (Box 7)
    - The Dust of Ages, Nov. 1958; article (Box 7)
    - The Dust of Death, Jan. 1957; article (Box 7)
    - The Egg and Wee, June 1962; article (Box 7)
    - The Element of Perfection, Nov. 1960; article (Box 7)
    - The Evens Have It, Aug. 1961; article (Box 7)
    - Exclamation Point, July 1965; article (Box 7)
    - Fecundity Limited, Jan. 1958; article (Box 7)
    - The Flickering Yardstick, March 1960; article (Box 7)
    - Four Steps to Salvation, June 1961; article (Box 7)
    - Future? Tense!, June 1965; article (Box 7)
    - Gimmicks Three, Nov. 1956; article (Box 7)
    - Harmony in Heaven, undated; article (Box 7)
    - Heaven on Earth, May 1961; article (Box 7)
    - The Height of Up, Oct. 1959; article (Box 7)
    - Here It Comes; There It Goes, Jan. 1961; article (Box 7)
    - He's Not My Type, Jan. 1963; article (Box 7)
    - Hot Stuff, July 1962; article (Box 8)
    - I Feel it in My Bones, Dec. 1957; article (Box 8)
    - I Just Make Them Up. See, Feb. 1958; article (Box 8)
    - The Imaginary That Isn't, March 1961; article (Box 8)
    - I'm In Marsport Without Hilda, Nov. 1957; article (Box 8)
    - I'M Looking Over A Four Leaf Clover, Sept. 1966; article (Box 8)
    - Insert Knob A in Hole B, 195/, Dec., article (Box 8)
    - The Isles of Earth, June 1966; article (Box 8)
    - Just Mooning Around, May 1963; article (Box 8)
    - The Land of Mu, Oct. 1965; article (Box 8)
    - The Light Fantastic, Aug. 1962; article (Box 8)
    - Life's Bottleneck, April 1959; article (Box 8)
    - The Lost Generation, Feb. 1963; article (Box 8)
    - The Lost Leonardo, March 1964; article (Box 8)
    - The Machine That Won The War, Oct. 1961; article (Box 8)
    - The Modern Demonology, Jan. 1962; article (Box 8)
    - My Built-in Doubter, April 1961; article (Box 8)
    - My Son, The Physicist, undated; article (Box 8)
    - The Noblemen of Science, April 1966; article (Box 8)
    - Not As We Know It, Sept. 1961; article (Box 8)
    - Now Hear This, Dec. 1960; article (Box 8)
    - Now Wakes the Sea, May 1963; article (Box 8)
    - Obituary, Aug. 1959; article (Box 8)
    - Oh, East is West and West is East, March 1965; article (Box 8)
    - Of Capture and Escape, May 1959; article (Box 8)
    - Old Man River, Nov. 1966; article (Box 8)
    - One, Ten Buckle My Shoe, Dec. 1962; article (Box 8)
    - Order! Order!, Feb. 1961; article (Box 8)
    - A Piece of Pi, May 1960; article (Box 8)
    - The Planet of the Sun, June 1959; article (Box 8)
    - Pre-Fixing It Up, Nov. 1962; article (Box 8)
    - The Proton Reckoner, Jan. 1966; article (Box 8)
    - Recipe for a Planet, July 1961; article (Box 9)
    - The Rigid Vacuum, April 1963; article (Box 9)
    - The Rocks of Damocles, 1966; article (Box 9)
    - Roll Call, Dec. 1963; article (Box 9)
    - The Shape of Things, undated; article (Box 9)
    - The Sight of Home, Feb. 1960; article (Box 9)
    - Slow Burn, Dec. 1962; article (Box 9)
    - Squ-u-u-ush!, Nov. 1965; article (Box 9)
    - Stepping Stones to the Stars, Oct. 1960; article (Box 9)
    - Superficially Speaking, Feb. 1962; article (Box 9)
    - The Symbol-Minded Chemist, Dec. 1966; article (Box 9)
    - T-Formation, Aug. 1963; article (Box 9)
    - That's About the Size of It, Oct. 1961; article (Box 9)
    - That's Life, Nov. 1962; article (Box 9)
    - Thin Air, Dec. 1959; article (Box 9)
    - Those Crazy Ideas, Jan. 1960; article (Box 9)
    - Time and Tide, May 1966; article (Box 9)
    - Tools of the Trade, Sept. 1960; article (Box 9)
    - To Tell a Chemist, May 1965; article (Box 9)
    - The Trojan Hearse, Dec. 1961; article (Box 9)
    - Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star, Sept. 1963; article (Box 9)
    - The Ultimate Split of the Second, Aug. 1959; article (Box 9)
    - Unto the Fourth Generation, March 1959; article (Box 9)
    - Up and Down the Earth, Feb.. 1966; article (Box 9)
    - The Up-To-Date Sorcerer, July 1958; article (Box 9)
    - Varieties of the Infinite, Sept. 1959; article (Box 9)
    - Water, Water, Everywhere, Dec. 1965; article (Box 9)
    - The Weighting Game, April 1962; article (Box 9)
    - Welcome Stranger, 1963; article (Box 9)
    - You, Too, Can Speak Gaelic, March 1963; article (Box 9)
    - Life Beyond the Earth, by V.A. Firsoff, undated; review (Box 9)
  - Austin, Mary
    - Night Thought, Sept. 1959; poem (Box 9)
  - Ayer, Ethom
    - Epitaph for the Future, Aug. 1964; poem (Box 9)
  - Ayme, Marcel
    - The State of Grace, Dec. 1959; article (Box 9)
    - The Ubiquitous Wife, Feb. 1961; article (Box 9)
    - The Walker-Through-Walls, Aug. 1959; article (Box 9)
  - Ballard, J.G.
    - The Garden of Time, Feb. 1962; article (Box 10)
    - The Illuminated Man, May 1964; article (Box 10)
  - Bankier, William
    - Unholy Hybrid, 1963; article (Box 10)
  - Banks, Raymond E.
    - Rabbits To The Moon, June 1959; article (Box 10)
    - The Revenant, Aug. 1960; article (Box 10)
  - Banks, Richard
    - Daddy's People, Feb. 1961; article (Box 10)
  - Barr, Stephen
    - The Homing Instinct of Joe Vargo, Dec. 1959; article (Box 10)
    - The Master of Altamirs, May 1964; article (Box 10)
    - Mr. Medley's Time Pill, May 1961; article (Box 10)
    - Oh I'll Take the High Road, July 1960; article (Box 10)
    - The Vandals, July 1958; article (Box 10)
    - Callahan and the Wheelies, Aug. 1960; book (Box 10)
  - Basch, Joan Patricia
    - Motog, undated; article (Box 10)
  - Beagle, Peter S.
    - Come Lady Death, Aug. 1966; article (Box 10)
  - Beauclerk, Jean
    - Lord Moon, Feb. 1964; article (Box 10)
    - We Serve the Star of Freedom, 1964; article (Box 10)
  - Beaumont, Charles
    - Father, Dear Father, Jan. 1957; article (Box 10)
    - The Science Fiction Screen, Dec. 1956; June 1957,; Nov. 1957,; Dec. 1957; article (Box 10)
  - Becker, Stephan
    - The New Encyclopaedist, May 1965; article (Box 10)
  - Benford, Greg
    - Flattop, May 1966; article (Box 10)
    - Representative from Earth, Jan. 1966; article (Box 10)
  - Bennett, Ken
    - A Different Purpose, Nov. 1950; article (Box 10)
  - Benton, Fred
    - Manlawe Jones, Aug. 1962; article (Box 10)
  - Bequaret, Frank
    - A Matter Organization, Aug. 1966; article (Box 10)
  - Berger, Josef
    - Maybe We Got Something, May 1959; article (Box 10)
  - Berry, Don
    - Intruder, Jan. 1958; article (Box 10)
  - Berry, John
    - Beyond Ganga Mata, June 1960; article (Box 10)
    - The Listener, Dec. 1960; article (Box 10)
    - The One Who Returns, March 1961; article (Box 10)
  - Bester, Alfred
    - The Black Nebulae, Sept. 1959; article (Box 11)
    - The Men Who Murdered Mohammed, Oct. 1958; article (Box 11)
    - They Don't Make Life Like They Used to, 1963; article (Box 11)
    - Book reviews, 1961; undated (Box 11)
  - Biggle, Lloyd, Jr.
    - Wings of Song, 1963; article (Box 11)
    - And Madly Teach, May 1966; book (Box 11)
  - Bland, Frederick
    - The Fifteenth Wind of March, June 1962; article (Box 11)
  - Blau, E. William
    - The Dispatch Executive, July 1961; article (Box 11)
  - Blish, James
    - This Earth of Hours, June 1959; article (Box 11)
    - In Memoriam: Fletcher Pratt, Jan. 1957; article (Box 11)
    - The Masks, Oct. 1959; article (Box 11)
    - No Jokes on Mars, Oct. 1965; article (Box 11)
    - The Oath, Oct. 1960; article (Box 11)
    - Theodore Sturgeon's Macrocosm, 1962; article (Box 11)
    - Who's In Charge Here?, May 1962; article (Box 11)
  - Bloch, Robert
    - The Conventional Approach, March 1964; article (Box 11)
    - The Plot is the Thing, July 1967; article (Box 11)
    - The Proper Spirit, March 1957; article (Box 11)
    - That Hell-Bound Train, Sept. 1958; article (Box 11)
  - Blum, Richard H.
    - The Firmin Child, Dec. 1965; article (Box 11)
  - Bonnet, Leslie
    - Game With A Goddess, Aug. 1959; article (Box 11)
  - Boone, Lincoln
    - The Corpse In Your Bed is Me, May 1957; article (Box 11)
  - Borgese, Elizabeth Mann
    - For Sale, Reasonable, June 1959; article (Box 11)
  - Boucher, Anthony
    - Gandolpher, Nov. 1956; article (Box 11)
    - The Pink Caterpillar, Dec. 1958; article (Box 11)
    - Recommended Reading, Jan.-Dec. 1957, 1958; reviews (Box 11)
  - Boyd, William C.
    - Will Time Wait, Sept. 1958; article (Box 12)
  - Brackett, Leigh
    - Purple Priestess of the Mad Moon, Oct. 1964; article (Box 12)
    - The Queer Jones, undated; book (Box 12)
  - Bradbury, Ray
    - Bright Phoenix, May 1963; article (Box 12)
    - The Chicago Abyss, May 1963; article (Box 12)
    - Death and the Maiden, March 1960; article (Box 12)
  - Bradley, Marion Zimmer
    - Another Rib, 1963; article (Box 12)
    - Bird of Prey, May 1957; book (Box 12)
  - Brandon, Carl
    - Stanley Toothbrush, July 1962; article (Box 12)
  - Breckenridge, Nicholas
    - The Cat Lover, July 1961; article (Box 12)
  - Brennan, J.H.
    - Final Appeal, Feb. 1965; article (Box 12)
  - Bretnor, R.
    - Bug-Getter, Dec. 1960; article (Box 12)
    - The Gadge System, Feb. 1966; article (Box 12)
    - Little Anton, Oct. 1964; article (Box 12)
    - The Man on Top, June 1960; article (Box 12)
    - Mrs. Pigafetta Swims Well, 1963; article (Box 12)
    - You Have To Know the Tune, Nov. 1962; article (Box 12)
  - Briarton, Grendel
    - Through Time and Space with Ferdinand Feghoot, 1958-1962, (folders 1-35), article (Box 12)
  - Brode, Anthony
    - Ballad of Outer Space, Nov. 1959; poem (Box 12)
    - The Better Bet, undated; poem (Box 12)
    - To Julia, Not To Gaze At Flying Saucers, Nov. 1960; poem (Box 12)
    - The Watchers, April 1958; poem (Box 12)
  - Browder, Albert
    - Contact Between Equals, July 1958; article (Box 12)
  - Brown, Fredric
    - Eine Kleine Nachtmusik, June 1965; article (Box 12)
    - Expedition, Feb. 1957; article (Box 12)
    - Unfortunately, Oct. 1958; article (Box 12)
  - Brown, Rosel George
    - Fruiting Body, Aug. 1962; article (Box 12)
    - Just A Suggestion, Aug. 1960; article (Box 12)
    - A Little Human Contact, Nov. 1960; article (Box 12)
    - Lost in Translation, May 1959; article (Box 12)
    - Off All Possible Worlds, Feb. 1961; article (Box 12)
    - The Ultimate Sin, Sept. 1961; article (Box 12)
  - Brunner, John
    - Protect Me From My Friends, Nov. 1962; article (Box 13)
    - Such Stuff, May 1962; article (Box 13)
    - The Productions of Time (Part I, Part II), Sept. 1966>; book (Box 13)
  - Buck, Doris Pitkin
    - Birth of a Gardener, June 1961; article (Box 13)
    - Girls Will Be Girls, Feb. 1966; article (Box 13)
    - Green Sunrise, Sept. 1961; article (Box 13)
    - The Little Blue Weeds of Spring, June 1966; article (Box 13)
    - Micky Finn, March 1966; article (Box 13)
    - Story of a Curse, June 1965; article (Box 13)
    - Classical Query Composed While Shampooing, June 1959; poem (Box 13)
    - Curved Universe, undated; poem (Box 13)
    - Epithalamium, Jan. 1958; poem (Box 13)
    - Lyric For Atom-Splitters, May 1957; poem (Box 13)
    - On Hearing Another Report of Little Green Men From..., April 1961; poem (Box 13)
    - The Respondents, 1963; poem (Box 13)
    - Vintage Wines, undated; poem (Box 13)
  - Budrys, Algis
    - About Something Truly Wonderful, Nov. 1961; article (Box 13)
    - The Edge of the Sea, March 1958; article (Box 13)
    - The Price, Feb. 1960; article (Box 13)
    - The Eye and the Lightning, Dec. 1958; book (Box 13)
    - Falling Torch, Jan. 1958; book (Box 13)
    - Machine, Dec. 1960; book (Box 13)
  - Bulgakov, Mikhail
    - The Fatal Eggs, Dec. 1964; book (Box 13)
  - Bulmer, Kenneth
    - The Adjusted, May 1966; article (Box 13)
  - Bunch, David R.
    - A Little Girl's Xmas in Modernia, Jan. 1960; article (Box 13)
  - Burger, Otis Kidwell
    - Love Child, May 1962; article (Box 14)
    - The Pleiades, 1963; article (Box 14)
    - The Zookeeper, May 1961; article (Box 14)
  - Calin, Herbert
    - The Hills of Lodan, April 1961; article (Box 14)
  - Campbell, Elizabeth K.
    - By The Crater of Tycho, Dec. 1957; poem (Box 14)
  - Cantine, Holley
    - Double, Double, Toil and Trouble, Jan. 1960; article (Box 14)
  - Capote, Truman
    - Master Misery, July 1962; article (Box 14)
  - Caravan, T.P.
    - Blind Date, April 1964; article (Box 14)
    - The Court of Tartary, 1963; article (Box 14)
  - Carr, A.H.Z.
    - It's Not My Fault, July 1960; article (Box 14)
  - Carr, John Dickson
    - New Murders for Old, Jan. 1957; article (Box 14)
  - Carr, Terry